Hello and welcome to this course overview
presentation for EVPC 321.
My name is Bruce Brazel,
along with Megan O'Connell.
We were the faculty assigned
to creating this course.
In this course,
you're going to be designing a solution
to take on an environmental challenge,
and you're going to be learning
about a approach to project planning
known as the logical frameworks.
So your course project
will involve these broad things.
Selecting a community
based environmental issue to tackle
planning a strategic initiative
to address the issue
using the logical framework approach.
And then finally,
you will create a project blueprint
that will bring a lot of pieces together.
So you'll have a cohesive plan to address
your chosen issue.
Now, there are a number of different kinds
of scenarios that you can take
to become the focus
of your course project.
The environmental issue
that you're choosing to explore
to give you a leg up on this.
Doctor O'Connell has created
three broad scenarios,
that deal with the three
big themes of this course.
The first is conservation.
So in scenario one, it
focuses on endangered
species
conservation in San Francisco Bay area.
The second theme is sustainability.
So scenario
two is environmental sustainability
in agriculture
and in business is Missouri.
And the third theme is regulatory
compliance and environmental justice.
So this particular scenario
is played out
in the petrochemical industry
and its impact on the folks
that live in the Houston, Texas region.
Now, you're not limited to these three,
but if you read through these scenarios,
you will see that there are different
options for you to, export.
You're definitely welcome to pick
a scenario that you find very interesting
that you're very passionate about,
to explore which project.
So here's our roadmap
to completing the course
project for EPC 321.
Our first step in week one will be
the creation of an annotated bibliography.
In week two
you will define the goals of the project.
The indicate errors
and the means of verification.
In week three,
you'll refine your project and populate,
the grid known as the log frame.
In week four,
you will construct your project Brief,
which will be a more detailed,
fleshed out components describing
the different aspects of your project
and the interested and effective persons,
the community that are going to benefit
or need to support your project.
And the final submission
is the Project Blueprint, which brings
all these components together.
So the annotated bibliography is basically
you're going to be selecting your course
project issue this week.
You're going to be conducting
a strategic literature search
to familiarize yourself with the topic
when you're not an expert in this field.
So we're going to be relying on
what has been published
previously by the experts,
and that is going to help
inform the different aspects
of your project development.
In week two,
we will be refining the project
goals, the indicators
and the means of verification.
So you're going to dive deeper in
to some of the items
you found in your previous review
of the literature in week one,
so this can help you develop your research
and foreign project goals.
The indicators or metrics,
those are going to be the measures
of progress and the success of the project
and the means of verification,
which is what is going to be measured
and how it's going to be measured.
The technology that's involved.
In week three,
you will populate your log frame.
So we'll be walking you
through that process.
So all the elements that you've collected
so far for weeks one and two,
that's going to pour into helping you
to build out your structured project plan.
And week four is the project brief,
where you're going to synthesize
what you've learned from the literature
and the development of your project plan
to create a very cohesive project,
narrative and justification
for addressing
this chosen environmental issue.
And then the final submission
is the project blueprint,
which is the culminating, task
in this course.
So it will consist of a title page, a
table of contents, annotated bibliography,
detailed description of the goals,
indicators and means of verification.
The log frame table, the project brief,
and of course, you will support it with,
an appendix with references
and the feedback table.
And the feedback table is going to be
a critical component of this
because one of the aspects of project
planning is involving your community,
involving stakeholders, involving
am interested
in effective persons or people.
And so while we are not actually
in the field
building your particular project,
we're going to simulate
that feedback, network
by the feedback
that your instructor is going to provide
you and the feedback that your peers in
the course are going to provide, you.
And the very last thing
that you will submit for this
course will be a presentation.
So you will create a video in which
you will pitch your plan to the community.
So not only you're going to be providing
details on what the project is about
and what it aims to do, but you're also
going to have to cover the why.
Because one of the things
that you will encounter in the real world
is you're going to need the community
behind you to support your project
and to continue
to support the project for its duration.
So that's a quick overview
of the course project for PC 321.
If you have any further questions,
please reach out to your instructor.